Milind Pandav

B-104, Alshwarya-Lakshmi Appt, Wagholi, Pune, India



Mobile phone:

+91-9823753573







2 SUMMARY

A motivated TIBCO Certified professional having ~ 8 y ars of experience in the Integration field powered by TIBCO and PaaS platforms. Well-versed in microservices, even -driven architectures, various APIs, API lifecycle & management horizon. Resourceful expert operating on customer engagement exercises involving presentations, POCs, customer escalation handling, & Account management, etc



SKILLS

TIBCO Products:

- BW Product Suite (5x, 6x, BWCE, TCI-BW) and different plugins/connectors
- TIBCO Cloud Integration Flogo and Flogo Enterprise & Connectors
- Messaging (EMS, eFTL, and Kafka)
- TIBCO Mashery
- TIBCO Cloud Events
- TIBCO Cloud Automate/Liveapps

Technology:

- Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Cloud Foundry-PCF,
- Amazon Services (good), Google Cloud (Basic), and Azure (Basic)

Programming Language:

Core JAVA

Database:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle

Tools and Utilities:

• SOAP UI, Jmeter, Postman, Wireshark, Visual Code, Eclipse, LDAP, etc.

Certifications:

- TIBCO Certified Professional:
 - TIBCO BusinessWorks Container Edition (BWCE)
 - TIBCO BusinessWorks
 - TIBCO Flogo Enterprise
 - TIBCO Messaging
- TIBCO Certified Associate:
 - TIBCO Cloud
 - TIBCO Mashery
 - TIBCO Cloud Events
- Microsoft Certified:
 - Azure Fundamental

EXPERIENCE

Senior Solution Engineer – TIBCO, *Pune*

11/2020 - Present

- Building open-source Solutions for TIBCO Cloud Integration Customers, solving real-world business problems.
- Coordinating with the Product Management and Product Engineering team to identify the gaps in products, relay the customer feedback using the right channel, and help in improving the overall product quality.
- Coordinating with the Product Management/Engineering team in building the customer, analyst demo's to advocate product capabilities as well as document those use-cases to reuse them for a general audience (customer, partners, presales, or field team).
- Being an advocate of field and customers relaying Product feedback to appropriate teams through the appropriate channels.
- Acted as a point-of-contact (and SME) between PM/Engineering team and onsite/onshore pre-sales during the customer POCs and customer engagements.
- Assist the sales and pre-sales team on TIBCO Connect portfolio products in an urgent or time-bound implementation or customer engagement.
- A significant contributor to work plans for components on engagements.

Senior Product Specialist — TIBCO, Pune

01/2014 - 10/2020

• Interacting with the client, provide solutions to different issues/errors they face, gathering the requirements, debugging,

- guiding the team members in case of any issues.
- Perceived expertise in multiple products like TIBCO BW product suite, TIBCO Hybrid Integration, TIBCO Messaging, and API Management.
- Work closely with the Product Engineering and Product Management team to highlight the product issues and customer requirements for improvement in the product.
- Work on POCs to fulfill the customer use case based on the requirements and demonstrate the capabilities of the product
- Learned the new TIBCO cloud product and the cloud-based technologies like DOCKER, K8S, Cloud Foundry, and Openshift to help the customer to solve their issues.
- Proactive work on escalated issues and problems to ensure adherence to customers' development schedule and also to avoid their business impact.
- Mentoring team members with Integration products as well as the PaaS Platforms.

OPENSOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

- Smart Transport Accelerator
- TIBCO Cloud Integration App M onitoring using platform APIs
- Various ready to use TIBCO Cloud Integration app templates available through TCI Marketplace

EDUCATION

Government College of Engineering – Bachelor of Engineering (2010 – 2013)

Computer Science

Indira Gandhi Polytechnic – Diploma (2007 – 2010)

Computer Science